现在我们理解了什么是确定性的加密
Now that we understand what is
deterministic encryption, let's see some
我们来看一些机制，能提供对抗
确定性的选择明文攻击的安全性
constructions that provide security
against deterministic chosen plaintext
首先我提醒大家，确定性的加密是需要的
attacks. So, first let me remind you that
the deterministic encryption is needed,
例如，当加密数据库索引时，稍后我们想查找记录
for example, when encrypting a database
index and later we wanna look up records
使用这个加密的索引。因为加密是确定性的
using the encrypted index. Because the
encryption is deterministic we're
我们保证，当我们查找加密的索引时
guaranteed that when we do the lookup the
encrypted index is gonna be identical to the
这个索引和当初记录被写进数据库时，给数据库的索引
encrypted index that was sent to the
database when the record was written to
是一样的。这样，这个确定性的加密可以让我们
the database. And so, this deterministic
encryption allows us a very simple or fast
以非常简单快捷的方式，根据加密的索引查找记录
way to do lookups based on encrypted
indices. The problem was that we said the
问题是我们说过，确定性加密不可能
对选择明文攻击是安全的
deterministic encryption can't possibility
be secure against a general chosen
因为如果攻击者看到两个相等的密文
plaintext attack because if the attacker
sees two cipher texts that are equal
他就知道了底层加密的明文信息是一样的
it learns that the underlying encrypted
messages are the same. So, then we defined
然后我们定义了确定性选择明文安全的概念
this concept of deterministic chosen plain
text security which means that we have
其意思是只要加密者不使用一个密钥多次加密同样的明文信息
security as long as the encryptor never
encrypts the same message more than once
我们就有安全性。特别地，这个密钥、明文信息对
只能使用一次
using a given key. In particular, this
key, message pair is only used once, for
对每次加密来说，要不密钥改变，要不明文信息改变
every encryption, either the key changes,
or the message changes. And then as I
然后我说过，我们形式化地定义这个CPA，
确定性的CPA安全游戏
said, formally we define this CPA,
deterministic CPA security game, and our
我们的本节的目标是给出确定性CPA安全的机制
goal in this segment is to actually give
constructions that are deterministic CPA
我们要看的第一个机制叫做SIV
secure. So the first construction we're
gonna look at is what's called SIV,
合成IV。这个机制的工作流程如下
synthetic IV's. And the way this
construction works is as follows. Imagine
我们有一个通用的CPA安全加密系统。这是密钥
we have a general CPA secure encryption
system. So here's the key and here's the
这是明文信息，我们把加密算法里使用的随机性记为R
message and we are gonna denote by R the
randomness that's used by the encryption
记得一个CPA安全系统不使用新鲜值的话
algorithm. Remember that a CPA secure
system that doesn't use nonce has to be
必须是随机的，所以我们直接写下这个变量R
randomized and so we're explicitly gonna
write down this variable R to denote the
来表示这个被用于加密算法的随机字符串
random string that's used by the
encryption algorithm as it's doing the
例如，如果我们使用随机计数器模式
encryption. For example if we're using
randomized counter mode, r would be the
R是随机IV，在随机计数器模式中被使用。
当然C是得到的密文
random IV that's used by randomized counter
mode. And of course C is the resulting
现在，我们还需要一个伪随机函数f
ciphertext. Now, in addition, we're also
going to need a pseudo random function, f,
这个函数f取信息空间里的任意信息作为输入
that what it does, is it takes our
arbitrary messages in the message space
输出一个字符串R，这个CPA安全的加密系统
可使用R作为随机性
and outputs a strings, R, that can be used
as randomness for the CPA secure
这里的r实际上是集合R的一个元素
encryption scheme. So, the little, r, over
here is actually a member of the big R set. Okay.
我们假设这个函数f是一个伪随机函数
And we're going to assume this is a, f is
a pseudo random function that maps messages
将明文信息映射到随机字符串。现在SIV如下工作
to random strings. Now the way SIV works
is as follows. It's going to use two keys
它使用两个密钥K1和K2来加密明文信息M
K1 and K2 to encrypt the message M. And
what it does, is the first thing is going
首先SIV应用伪随机函数f，根据明文M来推导
to apply the pseudo random function f to
the message M to derive randomness for the
用于CPA安全的加密机制E的随机性。然后
SIV使用推导出的随机性来加密明文M
CPA secure encryption scheme E. And then
it's going to encrypt the message M using
这会给我们一个密文C
the randomness that it just derived. This
is going to give us a cipher text C and
然后它将输出密文C。这就是SIV模式的工作流程
then it's going to output this cipher text
C Okay. So that's how this SIV mode works.
首先它从被加密的明文推导随机性
Basically it first derives the randomness
from the message being encrypted, and then
然后它使用这个推出的随机性来加密信息
it uses this derived randomness to
actually encrypt the message to obtain the
以获得密文。现在我想指出，比如说，如果加密机制E
cipher text. Now I'd like to point out for
example, if the encryption scheme E
正好是随机计数器模式的，那么随机性R
happened to be randomized counter mode.
Then the randomness R would just be the
就是随机IV，这个IV会随密文一并输出
random IV which would actually be output
along with the cipher text. So this means
这意味着密文比明文略长
that the cipher text is a little bit
longer than the plain text. But the point
但这里不是要去生成短密文，而是要确保
here isn't to generate a short cipher
text. Rather the point here is to make
加密机制的确定性，所以如果我们多次加密了同样的明文
sure that the encryption scheme is
deterministic, so if we encrypt the same
每次我们应当获得同样的密文
message multiple times, every time we
should obtain the same cipher text. And
其实每次我们都会获得同样的随机性R。因此
indeed every time, we'll obtain the same
randomness, R, and as a result, every time
每次我们都会获得同样的密文C。很容易证明
we'll obtain the same cipher text C. So
it's fairly easy to show that this
这个加密机制在确定的选择明文攻击下
encryption scheme really is semantically
secure under the deterministic chosen
是语义安全的。其原因是我们应用伪随机函数F
plaintext attack. The reason that's so
is because we apply the pseudo random
来处理多个信息。如果我们应用F来处理多个信息
function F to distinct messages. Well if
we apply F to distinct messages then the
那么F生成的随机字符串将看起来像是真随机字符串
random string that F generates is going to
look like just truly random strings. A
每条信息都有不同的随机字符串。因此
different random string for every message.
And as a result the CPA secure encryption
这个CPA安全的加密机制总是使用真随机字符串
scheme E is always applied using truly
random strings. And that's exactly the
这正是它是CPA安全的情形。因为这些R是随机的
situation where it is CPA secure. So
because these R's are just random
与新字符串不可区分，所以实际上得到的机制
indistinguishable from brand new strings,
the resulting system is in fact gonna be
是CPA安全的。这只是为什么SIV有效的直观理解
CPA secure. So this is just the intuition
for why this works and it's actually
实际上很容易就能形式化为一个完整的证明
fairly straightforward to actually
formalize this into a complete proof. Now,
我应该强调，这对多于一个AES分组的明文来说
I should emphasize that this is actually
well suited for messages that are more
特别合适。事实上，对于短明文信息，我们将看到
than one AES block. In fact, for short
messages, we're gonna see a slightly
一个稍有不同的加密机制，更适合这些短明文信息
different encryption scheme that's
actually better suited for these short
现在SIV的一个很好是事实是
messages. Okay, now the really cool thing
about SIV is that, actually, we get cipher
我们免费获得了密文完整性。事实上，
我们不必使用特定的MAC，如果想加上完整性的话
text integrity for free. In fact we don't
have to use a special MAC if we want to
某种意义上SIV已经构建了完整性机制
add integrity. In a sense SIV already has
a built in integrity mechanism. And let me
我来解释一下我的意思。首先，我们的目标是构建
explain what I mean by that. First of all,
our goal was to build what's called
所谓的确定性的认证加密(DAE)
deterministic authenticated encryption.
DAE. Deterministic Authenticated
确定性的认证加密意思是：确定性的CPA安全加上
Encryption. Which basically means that
deterministic CPA security and cipher text
密文完整性。记得密文完整性的意思是，攻击者询问
integrity. Remember cipher text integrity
means that the attacker gets to ask for
他选择的信息的加密结果，而他不能产生
the encryptions of messages of his choice
and then he shouldn't be able to produce
另一个密文可以被解密成有效的明文
another cipher text that decrypts to a
valid message. Okay, so I want to claim
我想断言，事实上SIV自动地给出了一个密文完整性
that in fact SIV automatically gives a
cipher text integrity without the need for
不需要嵌入MAC或其他东西。我们来看为什么
an embedded MAC or anything else. So let's
see why. In particular, let's look at a
我们看一个SIV的特例，其底层的加密机制是
special case of SIV when the underlying
encryption scheme is randomized counter
随机计数器模式。我们记之为SIV-CTR，表示
mode. Okay, so we'll call this SIV-CTR
again to denote SIV where we're using
使用随机计数器模式的SIV。我再提醒一下大家
randomized counter mode. Alright. So let
me remind you again how SIV works in this
这种情况下SIV是如何工作的。我们取明文信息
case. Well, so we take our message, here,
we take our message, and then we apply a
然后对明文应用PRF，推导出一个IV，然后IV被用在
PRF to it. And that derives an IV. And
then that IV is going to be used to
加密明文信息，使用随机计数器模式。特别地
encrypt the message using randomized
counter mode. Okay. So in particular,
我们要使用这个PRF Fctr表示F计数器，随机计数器模式
we're gonna use this PRF Fctr for F
counter, for randomized counter mode and
计算Fctr在IV处的值，在IV+1处的值，一直到IV+L
essentially evaluate this Fctr at IV, IV
plus one up to IV plus L. And, then, we
然后得到这么样的一个信息。那就给了我们最终的密文
had sort of that with the message. And that
gives us the final ciphertext. Okay. So,
这是用随机计数器模式的SIV。现在，我们看如何解密
this is SIV with a randomized counter
mode. Now, let's see how decryption is
在解密过程中，我们增加一个检查
gonna work. And during decryption we're
gonna add one more check, and that's
以提供密文完整性。我们看解密如何工作的
going to provide ciphertext integrity. So let's see
how decryption is going to work. So here
这里我们有包含IV和密文的输入密文
we have our input cipher text that
contains the IV and the cipher text. Well,
首先我们将使用给定的IV解密密文
the first thing we're going to do is we're
going to decrypt the cipher text using the
我们会得到一个候选明文。现在我们再次应用
given IV, and that will give us candidate
plain text. Now we're gonna reapply the
PRF F来处理这个得到的明文信息，
根据SIV的定义。如果得到的明文有效
PRF F from the definition of SIV to this
message. Now if a message is valid, we
我们应该获得与攻击者在密文中所提供的同样的IV
should be getting the same IV that the
adversary supplied as part of the cipher
如果我们得到一个不同的IV，那么我们知道了
这个得到的明文不是有效的
text. If we get a different IV, then we
know that this message is not a valid
我们就拒绝这个密文。这真犀利
message and we simply reject the cipher
text. So this is really acute. It's a very
很容易构建检查以确保密文是有效的
simple kinda built in check to make sure
that the cipher text is valid, right. We
我们在解密后检查，我们重新推出的IV是否
simply check that after decryption if
we re-derive the IV we would actually get
是正确的IV。如果不是我们就拒绝。我说
the correct IV. And if not we reject the
message. And I claim that this simple check
解密中的这个检查实际上足以提供密文完整性。所以
during decryption is enough to actually provide
ciphertext integrity. And therefore,
确定性的认证加密。我要用一个简单的定理来表述之
deterministic authenticated encryption. So
I'll state this in a simple theorem.
如果F是一个安全的PRF，在计数器模式中
Basically to say, that if F is a secure
PRF, and in counter mode that's derived
这是由CPA安全的Fctr推出的，然后事实上
得到的机制是确定性的认证加密系统
from Fctr is CPA secure, then the result
is in fact a deterministic authenticated
现在这个定理的证明不难。两句话
encryption system. Now the proof for this
is not too difficult. In two sentences,
我就告诉大家这个定理成立的直观理解
let me just show you the rough intuition
for why this is true. So, all we have to
我们只需要证明密文完整性。我们之前已经证明了
argue is just cipher text integrity. So we
already argued before that the system has
这个系统有确定性的CPA安全性。我们只需证
它具有密文完整性
deterministic CPA security, all we have to
argue is just cipher text integrity. So to
为了证明这个系统有密文完整性，我们看
argue that the system has cipher text
integrity, let's think again how the
这个密文完整性是如何工作的。攻击者询问
cipher text integrity game works.
Adversary asks for the encryption of a
一组他选择的明文的加密结果，然后他获得相应的密文
bunch of messages of his choice. And he
gets the resulting cipher text. Then, his
攻击者的目标是产生一个新的有效的密文。
如果这个有效密文在解密时
goal is to produce a new valid cipher
text. Well, if that valid cipher text upon
被解密成了某个全新的明文，那么我们
decryption, decrypts to some completely
new message. Then when we plug this new
把这个新信息带入PRF F，我们将获得某个随机IV
message into the PRF F, we're just going to
get some random IV and it's very unlikely
这个IV基本上不可能是攻击者在输出的密文中提供的IV
to hit the IV that the adversary supplied
in the cipher text that he output. So
所以这就是说，当攻击者输出他的伪造的密文时
therefore that says that when the adversary
outputs his forged cipher text, the
伪造的密文里的信息应该等于他在
message in that forged cipher text
basically should be equal to one of the
选择明文询问里得到的信息之一。否则，得到的IV
messages in his chosen message queries.
Otherwise, again the IV that you get is
以很高的概率不等于伪造的密文中提供的IV
simply not gonna be equal to the IV in the
forged cipher text with very high
但如果明文等于攻击者问过我们的明文之一
probability. But if the message is equal
to one of the messages that the adversary
那么我们得到的密文将等于
queried us on, well then, the cipher text
that we're gonna get is also gonna be
我们提供给攻击者的密文之一
equal to one of the cipher texts that we
supplied to the adversary. But then his
那就是说，攻击者的伪造密文就是我们曾给他的密文之一
forgery is simply one of the cipher texts
that we gave to him. And therefore, this
所以这不是一个有效的伪造。攻击者必须给我们
一个新的密文，来赢得这场密文完整性游戏
is not a valid forgery. He has to give us
a new cipher text to win the cipher text
但他给我们一个老的密文。那么这是大致的想法
integrity game. But he gave us one of our
old cipher texts. So, this is the rough
我想快速讲完，并且有道理
intuition. I hope, I kinda went through it
quickly. I hope it kinda makes sense. If
如果不明白也没多大事。我将参考一篇关于SIV的论文
it doesn't then it's not the end of the
world. I'm gonna reference the paper that
在本章最后。如果大家想了解更多细节
describes SIV at the end of the module.
And if you wanna see this in more detail
可以去阅读这篇论文。但是
you can read and take a look inside of
that paper. But, regardless, this is a
这个想法很犀利，我想展示给大家这个事实
very acute idea that I wanted to show you
where kinda the fact that we derive the
我们使用PRF从确定性的计数器模式来推导出随机性
randomness for deterministic counter mode
using a PRF. Also, gives us an integrity
我们在解密时进行一个完整性检查。这个SIV是个好模式
check when we actually do the decryption.
Okay. So this SIV is a good mode for doing
当你需要进行确定性的加密时，特别是当明文很长时
deterministic encryption when you need to,
particularly if the messages are long. If
如果明文很短，比如说少于16个字节的话
the messages are very short, say they're
less than sixteen bytes, in fact there's a
事实上有个更好的办法，我现在想告诉大家这个办法
better way to do it, and that's the method
that I wanna show you now. So the second
这第二个机制很简单。我们只需要直接使用PRP
construction is actually trivial. All
we're gonna do is we're gonna use a PRP
我们这样做，假设(E,D)是一个安全的PRP。E是加密
directly. So here's what we do. So suppose
(E, D) is a secure PRP. So E will encrypt, and
D是解密。我断定，如果我们直接使用E
D will decrypt. And I claim that if we use
E directly, that already gives us
就已经给了我们确定性CPA安全性。我来简单证明一下。
假设F是从X到X的真随机可逆函数
deterministic CPA security. So let me show you very quickly why. So suppose F is a truly random invertible function from X
记得PRP与真随机可逆函数不可区分
to X. Okay. So remember a PRP is
indistinguishable from a truly random
那么我们假定我们所有的就是一个
invertible function, so let's pretend that
we actually do have a truly random
真随机可逆函数。现在在实验0里，攻击者将看到
invertible function. Now in experiment
zero what the attacker is gonna see while
他提交的一组明文信息，也就是左边的信息
he submits a bunch of messages, you know
the messages on the left. And what he's
攻击者会看到函数f在左边信息上的值
gonna see is basically the evaluation of f
on the messages on the left that he
在这个确定性的CPA游戏里，所有这些信息都不一样
supplied. Well, in the deterministic CPA
game, all these messages are distinct, and
他会得到q个不同的X中的随机值。他只能看到这些
so all he's gonna get back are just q
distinct random values in X. That's all he
是的，有q个X中的不同的值。现在，我们想想实验1
sees. Yes, there's Q distinct random
values in X. Now let's think about
在实验1中，攻击者收到右边信息的加密
experiment one. In experiment one, he gets
to see the encryptions of messages on the
从M11到Mq1。所有这些信息也都是不相同的
right, okay, the M11 to MQ1. Well, again,
all these messages are all distinct so all
所以攻击者还是获得q个X中的随机的不同值
he gets to see are just Q random distinct
values in X. Well these two distributions,
实验0和实验1的这两个分布是相等的
in experiment zero and experiment one,
therefore are identical. Basically, in
在两种情况下，攻击者都只能收到q个随机的X中的不同值
both cases what he gets to see are just Q
distinct random values in X. And as a
因此，他不能区分实验0和实验1
result, he can't distinguish experiment
zero from experiment one. And since he
由于他对真随机函数不能区分，他对这个PRP也不能
can't do this for a truly random function,
he also can't do this for the PRP. Ok,
这就解释了为什么直接用PRP加密已经给了我们
so that explains why directly encrypting
with a PRP already gives us a CPA secure
一个CPA安全系统，非常容易使用。这说明，如果我们
system very, very, very simple to use.
That says that if all we wanna do is
只想加密短信息，比如说，少于16字节的信息
encrypt short messages, say, less than
sixteen bytes, then all we need to do is
我们只需要直接使用AES加密它们，得到的结果事实上
to directly encrypt them using AES and the
result will, in fact, be deterministic CPA
就是确定性的CPA安全的。那么如果你的目录少于16字节
secure. So, if your indices are less than
sixteen bytes directly using AES is a fine
完全可以直接使用AES。但是，注意这不会提供任何完整性
thing to do. Notice however, that's not
gonna provide any integrity. And we're
我们待会将看到如何加入完整性。不过给大家的问题是
gonna see how to add integrity in just a
minute. But the question for you is, what
如果我们的明文长于16个字节，怎么办？
do we do if we have longer than sixteen
byte messages? Well, one option is to use
一个方法是使用SIV。但是如果我还想使用这个机制
SIV. But what if we actually wanted to use
this construction too. It's actually an
这是个有趣的问题。我们能不能构建PRP
interesting question. Can we construct
PRP's that have message spaces that are
它的明文空间比16个字节大？如果大家还记得
bigger than just sixteen bytes? If you
remember in the past we constructed PRFs
我们曾根据小明文空间的PRF，组建过大明文空间的PRF
on that had large message spaces from
PRFs that had small message spaces. Here,
这里，我们要组建大明文空间的PRP
we're going to construct PRPs with large
message spaces from PRFs that have small
从小明文空间的PRF出发。我们这么做。
假设E,D是一个安全的PRP
message spaces. So, here's how we do it.
So suppose E D is a secure PRP that
定义在n位分组上。有一个标准模式叫做EME
operates on N bit blocks. There's a
standard mode called EME that actually
会组建一个定义在N位分组上的PRP
will construct a PRP that operates on
capital N bit blocks, where capital N is
N远远大于n。那么这使得我们可以进行确定性加密
much, much bigger than little n. So this
would allow us to do deterministic
能加密长于16字节的明文信息。事实上
encryption on much larger messages than
just sixteen bytes. In fact it could be as
只要我们想，就可以的。我们看看EME然后工作的
开始时会有点吓人
long as we want. So let's see how EME
works. It's a bit daunting at first but
但这个机制并不难。我们看看它是如何工作的
it's not a difficult construction. So,
let's see how it works. So, EME uses two
EME使用了两个密钥K和L，事实上在EME中，L是由K推出的
keys, K and L, and in fact in the real EME
L is derived from K. But for our purposes,
不过为了我们的目标，我们假定K和L是不同的密钥
let's just pretend that K and L are two
distinct keys. The first thing we do, is
首先我们取明文X，把它分解成若干分组
we take our message X and we break it up
into blocks. And then we XOR each block
然后把每个分组都异或一个特定的密码本函数。
我们使用密钥L来推导一个密码本
with a certain padding function, okay? So
we use the secret key L to derive a pad
使用这个函数P。我这里解释一下
using this, you know function P that I'm
not gonna explain here. We derive a
我们对每个分组推导一个不同的密码本，然后
我们计算这个密码本和分组的异或
different pad for each one of the blocks
and we XOR that pad into the block. The
接下来我们应用PRP E，使用密钥K，对每个分组进行操作
next thing we do is we apply the PRP E
using the Key K, to each of these blocks,
我们叫这些输出为PP0, PP1和PP2。接下来
and we're gonna call these outputs PP0,
PP1, and PP2. The next thing we do is we
我们把所有PPP异或起来，我们叫异或结果为MP
XOR all these ppp's together and we call
the result MP. Actually this XOR
实际上这步异或不是必需的。我们把这个结果的异或称为MP
doesn't need to be there. We call the
result of the XOR MP. The next thing we
接下来我们把这些PPP异或起来，称结果为MP
do we XOR all these ppp's together and we
call the result MP. We encrypt this MP
我们用E和密钥K来加密这个MP。我们把加密的输出叫做MC
using E and the key K. We call the outputs of
this encryption MC. Okay. So then we use
然后我们计算MP异或MC，得到另一个PM，我们使用这个PM
the XOR MP and MC and this gives us
another PM, which we use to derive one
来推导更多的密码本，然后我们把这个密码本的输出
和所有PPP异或
more pad, and then we XOR this output
of this pad with all the PPP's to get
得到这些CCC，然后我们把所有这些CCC异或
these CCC's, ha, and then we XOR
all these CCC's together that gives us
我们得到一个值叫CCC0，然后我们再加密一次，使用这些E
a value of CCC zero, which we then
encrypt one more time with all these E's,
我们用这些P做更多的密码本。最后我们得到
we do one more padding with all these P's
and that actually finally gives us the
EME的输出。所有我说了，这可能看起来有点吓人
output of EME. Okay, so like I said,
this may look a little daunting, but in
但事实上，有个定理证明了，如果底层分组密码E
fact there's a theorem that shows that if
the underlying block cipher E is a secure
是个安全的PRP，这个EME机制在这个大分组上是安全的PRP
PRP, then in fact. This construction, EME,
is a secure PRP on this larger block, you
即｛0,1｝^N。这个机制的好处是
know, zero, one to the capital N. The nice
thing about this construction is you
它是可并行的，这也是它为什么有点复杂的原因
notice that it's very parallel and
actually that's why it's a little
每个分组并行加密，如果你有一个多核处理器
complicated. Counted every block. It's
encrypted in parallel, so if you have a
你可以使用你的所有核来同时加密这些分组
multi-core processor, you can use all your
cores to encrypt all the blocks at the
然后有一点串行的步骤要计算
same time and then there would be one kind
of sequential step to compute this, check
计算输出的校验和，然后再来一次并行操作
sum of, all the outputs and then one more
parallel around to encrypt one more time
再加密一次，然后最终获得输出。这些函数P
and then finally you get the outputs.
These function Ps, by the way, that
用于生成密码本的，是非常简单的函数。它们需要常数的时间
generate the pads, are very, very simple
functions. They take constant time so
所以评估性能时，我们将忽略它们
we're just going to ignore them in terms
of performance. So the bottom line is
所以这里性能的底线是，大家注意对每个输入分组
它要求运用E两次
performance here. You notice it requires
two applications of E per input block. And
事实上EVE可能比SIV慢很多，如果SIV被合理实现
it turns out this can actually be slower
than SIV, if SIV is implemented properly
使用了很快的PRF来推导随机性。然后事实上
with a very fast PRF to derive the
randomness. Then in fact SIV can be twice
SIV可以比这种操作模式快出一倍。其原因，我说
as fast, as this particular mode of
operation. For this reason I say that the
PRP机制擅长处理短明文信息，而SIV擅长处理
PRP construction is very good for short
messages, whereas SIV is good if you h, if
长信息的加密，以确定的方式。但现在
you want to encrypt longer messages in a
deterministic fashion. But now what if we
如果我们想对这个基于PRP的机制加上完整性，怎么办？
wanted to add integrity to this PRP-based
mechanism? So, can we achieve
我们能否获得确定的认证加密，使用PRP机制
deterministic authenticated encryption
using the PRP mechanism where we directly
直接用PRP来加密信息呢？实际上答案是肯定的
encrypt the message using a PRP? And it
turns out the answer is yes and it's
实际上是一个非常简单的加密机制，大家应该知道的
actually again, a very simple
encryption scheme that you should know
我们取我们的明文信息
about. Basically what we're going to do is
we're going to take our message and we're
然后在信息后面附一堆0，然后应用PRP
going to append a bunch of zeros to this
message and then we're going to apply the
就完事了。这样做会给我们密文。非常简单
PRP and that's it. And that's going to
give us the cipher text. Now, very, very
只要附0，然后用PRP加密。当我们解密时
simple. Just append zeros and encrypt
using a PRP. When we decrypt, we're going
我们看获得的明文的这些低位
to look at these least significant bits of
the resulting plain text and if they're
如果它们不等于0，我们将拒绝这个密文
not equal to zero, we're just going to
reject the cipher text. And if they are
如果它们等于0，我们将输出有效信息。好了，完事
equal to zero, we're going to output the
message as valid. Okay, so that's it,
这是整个系统，非常简单。加密时把0附在后面
that's the whole system, very, very
simple. Simply append zeroes during
然后解密时，检查这些零还在不在
encryption, and then check that the zeroes
are there when you decrypt. And I claim
我说，这个非常简单的机制实际上提供了确定的
that this very simple mechanism actually
provides deterministic authenticated
认证加密，当然前提是你附了足够多的0
encryption, assuming, of course, that
you've appended enough zeroes. And in
特别地，如果你附了N个0，你需要1除以2的N次方
particular, if you append N zeroes, you
need one over two to the N to be
是可忽略的。如果是这样，事实上，这个直接的
基于PRP的加密，事实上
negligible. And if so, then, in fact, this
direct PRP based encryption, in fact,
提供了确定性的认证加密。让我看看为什么
provides deterministic authenticated
encryption. So let me see why. Well, we
我们已经论证了这个系统是CPA安全的
already argued that the system is CPA
secure, so all we have to argue is that it
所以我们只需论证，它提供了密文完整性。
这是容易看出来的。我们看这个
provides cipher text integrity. And again,
that's easy to see. Let's look at the
密文游戏。攻击者选择，我们说一个真随机置换
cipher text game. So the adversary
is gonna choose let's say a truly random
那么，一个输入空间上的真随机可逆函数
permutation. So a truly random, invertible
function, on the input space. In this case
在这个情况下，输入空间是明文空间和N位0
the input space is the message space and
the N zero bits. Now what does the
攻击者怎么办？他会提交q个明文信息
adversary get to do? Well he gets to
submit q messages, and then he receives
然后他收到了这q个明文信息的加密结果。
他收到了他选择的点联结上N位0后对应的PRP的值
the encryption of those Q messages. Mainly
he receives the PRP at his chosen points
好，这就是他要问CPA挑战者的
concatenated with N zeros. Okay, that's
what it basically it means to query the
对于随机置换来说，他会看到
CPA challenger. So in case of a random
permutation, he simply gets to see, the
这个置换在他选的q个点的值，别忘了附上N位0
value of this permutation at Q points of
his choice, but only concatenated with N
现在，在这个密文完整性游戏中，攻击者的目标是什么？
zeroes. And now, what's his goal in the
cipher text integrity game? Well, his goal
他的目标是产生一些新的密文，与他之前获得的密文都不同
is to produce some new cipher text that's
different from the cipher text that he was
这些新密文可以顺利解密。那顺利解密是什么意思？
given, that's gonna decrypt properly.
Well, what does it mean that it decrypts
它的意思是，当我们对密文C应用逆置换后
properly? It means that if, when we apply,
Pi inverse to the cipher text C, it had
C的最低N位最好都是0
better be the case that the N least
significant bytes of C are all zeros. And
(这里的C已经是应用过逆置换后的值)
问题是这个发生的可能性有多大呢？我们想一想
the question is how likely is that to
happen? Well, so let's think about this.
那么我们有一个真随机置换，攻击者可以看到
So basically we have a truly random
permutation and the adversary got to see
这个置换在q个点的值。他产生一个新点
the value of this permutation as Q points.
How likely is he to produce a new point
当求逆过后，最低N位正好都是0的概率是多少？
that, when inverted, happens to have N zeroes
as the least significant bits? What we're
我们这里在计算这个逆置换在点C的值
doing here is basically we're evaluating
the permutation Pi inverse at the point c.
因为逆置换是一个随机置换
And since Pi inverse is a random
permutation, how likely is it to have its
它最低N位正好都是0的可能性有多大？
不难看出答案是
n least significant bits be equal to zero?
So it isn't hard to see that the answer
这个概率最多是1除以2的N次方
is, is, at most, the probability's at
most, one over two to the N. Because,
因为这个置换会输出X乘以｛0,1｝^N中的一个随机元素
again, basically, the permutation is gonna
output a random element inside of, X times
(这里的乘法乃字符串联结使然)
这个元素以N位0结尾
0 1 to the N. And that element is gonna end
with N zeroes, but basically
以概率1除以2的N次方。因此攻击者
with the probability one over two to the
N. And as a result, the adversary wins the
以可忽略的概率赢得这场游戏，因为这个值是可忽略的
game with negligible probability, Because,
this value is negligible. So that's the
本节完结。我想让大家看两个非常犀利的
end of this segment. I wanted you to see
these two very acute deterministic
认证加密机制。第一个叫做SIV
authenticated encryption schemes. The
first one we called SIV, where I said you
我说过大家可以使用随机计数器模式，可以获得随机性
would use randomized counter mode and you
just arrived at randomness for randomized
对明文信息应用PRF的随机计数器模式。
这里一个很犀利的想法是
counter mode from a PRF applied to the
message. And the very acute idea here is
在解密过程中，你可以根据解密的信息重新计算IV
that during decryption you can simply
recompute the IV from the, from the decrypted
并验证这个IV是否是在密文中给的IV
message and verify that that IV is what's
given to you in the cipher text. And that
这个简单的检查实际上足以保证认证加密
simple check is actually enough to
guarantee authenticated encryption or
甚至能保证确定的认证加密
rather deterministic authenticated
encryption. So this mode is, is the way
如果数据库的索引很长，大家可以用这个模式
来加密这个索引
you would encrypt an index in a database
if the index was large. If the index
如果这个索引正好较短，比如说，可能是8字节的用户ID
happens to be short, maybe say, its eight
bytes if it's an 8-byte user ID, then you
那么大家可以直接使用PRP，可以在这8个字节后面附0
can directly use a PRP and the way you
would do is, is you would append zeros to
然后这些0可以被用来作为完整性检测
those eight bytes. And then those zeros
will be used as an integrity check when
当大家解密后，如果能够附足够多的0
you decrypt and again if you append, are
able to append enough zeros, then in fact
那么事实上，这也提供了确定的认证加密
this also provides deterministic
authenticated encryption. As an aside, I
另外，我还给大家看了一个构建宽分组的PRP的方法
showed you that there's a way to build the
wide block PRP from a narrow PRP and that
是由窄分组的PRP构建的，这个操作模式叫做EME
particular mode of operation is called
EME. So we're gonna refer EME
下节中我们还要看EME
actually in the next segment.